{
	"questions": [
		{
			"question": "Where, in any specific case, different sections of this code specify different materials, methods of construction or other requirements, the most _________ shall govern.",
			"answer": ["restrictive"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The purpose of this code is to establish __________ requirements to safeguard the public safety, health and general welfare.",
			"answer": ["minimum"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where a referenced code or standard includes sugject matter that is within the scope of the IRC, the provisions of the _____ shall take precedence.",
			"answer": ["IRC"]
		},
		{
			"question": "An alternative material or method shall be approved where the proposed design is ______ and complies with the ______ of the code.",
			"answer": ["satisfactory", "intent"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Compliance with the specific _______-based provisions of the International Codes in Lieu of specific requirements of the IRC shall be permitted as an alternative.",
			"answer": ["performance"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A permit is not required for one-story detached accessory structures, provided that the floor area does not exceed ______ square feet.",
			"answer": ["200"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Fences that are _____ feet or less in height do not require a permit.",
			"answer": ["7"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A permit is not required for the replacement of branch circuit overcurrent devices (breakers) of the required capacity in the same location (within a panel).",
			"answer": ["True"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Unattached decks not exceeding ______ square feed in area, that are not more than ________ inches above grade at any point, do not require a permit.",
			"answer": ["200", "30"],
			"note": "provided the decks do not serve the exit door required by Section R311.4."
		},
		{
			"question": "Where equipment replacements and repairs must be performed in an emergency situation, the permit application shall be submitted within the _________ _______ business days.",
			"answer": ["next working"]
		},
		{
			"question": "An application for a permit for any proposed work shall be deemed to have been abandoned _______ days after the date of filing.",
			"answer": ["180"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Before issuing a permit, the building official is ________ to examine or cause to be examined buildings, structures and sites for which an application has been filed.",
			"answer": ["authorized"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where the building official issues a permit, the construction documents shall be approced in writing or by a stamp which states _______ ________ ________ ________.",
			"answer": ["Reviewed for code compliance"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Final inspection shall be made after the permitted work is ___________ and prior to _______",
			"answer": ["complete", "occupancy"]
		},
		{
			"question": "If located in a flood hazard area, the documentation of elevations required in Section R322,.1.10 shall be submitted to the building offical prior to the ________ inspection.",
			"answer": ["final"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Signifies access that requires the removal of an access panel or similar removable obstruction.",
			"answer": ["Access (to)"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A finished or unfinished habitable space within an attic.",
			"answer": ["Attic room (habitable attic)"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Hot water is water at a temperature greater than or equal to ________ degrees Fahrenheit.",
			"answer": ["110"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A wall supporting a vertical load in addition to its own weight is a ________-________ wall.",
			"answer": ["load","bearing"]
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the minimum uniformly distributed live load for habitable attics and attics served with fixed stairs?",
			"answer": ["30 psf"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Wood structural panels with a minimum thickness of _______ inch and a maximum span of _______ feet shall be permitted for opning protection in windborne debris regions.",
			"answer": ["7/16", "8"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The seismic provisions of the IRC apply to detached one- and two-family dwellings in Seismic Design Categories __________.",
			"answer": ["D0","D1","D2"]
		},
		{
			"question": "For dwellings with fire sprinkler systems, exterior walls with a fire seperation distance less than ________ feet shall have not less than a 1-hour fire-resistance rating with exposure from the outside.",
			"answer": ["3"]
		},
		{
			"question": "In a nonspriklered townhouse building, the common wall between units shall be a minimum of _______ - hour _______ - __________ __________ wall assembly.",
			"answer": ["2","fire-resistance rated"]
		},
		{
			"question": "For townhouse separation, a parapet is not required where the roof sheathing is fire-retardant-treated wood for a distance of __________ feet on each side of the wall and there are no penetrations in the roof within _________ feet of the common wall.",
			"answer": ["4", "4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Openings from a private garage directly into a room used for _______ ________ shall not be permitted.",
			"answer": ["sleeping purposes"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Doors between the garage and residence shall be equipped with a _____ - ________ ________.",
			"answer": ["self-closing or automatic closing device"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Garages shall be separated from residences and attics by not less than ________ - inch gypsum board or equivalent on the garage side.",
			"answer": ["1/2"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Enclosed space under stairs that is accessed by a door or access panel shall have walls, under-stair surface and any soffits protected on the enclosed side with _______ - inch gypsum board.",
			"answer": ["1/2"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Wall and ceiling finishes shall have a flame spread index of not greater than ___________.",
			"answer": ["200"]
		},
		{
			"question": "In combustible construction, fireblocking shall be provided to cut off all concealed draft openings and to form an effective fire barrier between _________.",
			"answer": ["stories"]
		},
		{
			"question": "All habitable rooms shall be provided with aggregate glazing area of not less than ________ percent of the floor area of such rooms.",
			"answer": ["8"]
		},
		{
			"question": "For natural ventilation for habitable rooms, the minimum openable area to the outdoors shall be ________ percent of the floor area being ventilated.",
			"answer": ["4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Bathrooms shall be provided with aggregate glazing area in windows of not less than _______ square feet, one-half of which must be openable.",
			"answer": ["3"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where the air infiltration rate of a dwelling unit is not more than _________ air changes per hour where tested, the dwelling unit shall be provided with _______ - ________ mechanical ventilation.",
			"answer": ["5", "whole","house"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Dwelling units shall be provided with heating facilities capable of maintaining a minimum room temperature of ________ degrees Fahrenheit.",
			"answer": ["68"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Habitable rooms shall have a floor area of not less than _______ square feet.",
			"answer": ["70"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Habitable rooms shall be not less than _______ feet in any horizontal dimension.",
			"answer": ["7"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Habitable space, hallways and portions of basements containing these spaces shall have a ceiling height of not less than _______ feet.",
			"answer": ["7"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Bathrooms, toilet rooms and aluncdry rooms shall have a minimum ceiling height of _________ feet _______ inches",
			"answer": ["6","8"]
		},
		{
			"question": "For rooms with sloped ceilings, at least ______ percent of the required floor area of the room must have a ceiling height of not less than 7 feet.",
			"answer": ["50"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Portions of basements that do not contain habitable space or hallways shall have a ceiling height of not less than _________ feet ________ inches.",
			"answer": ["6","8"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Every dwelling unit shall be provided with a water closet, lavatory, and a ______ or _______.",
			"answer": ["bathtub", "shower"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Each dwelling unit shall be provided with a kitchen area and every kitchen area shall be provided with a _________.",
			"answer": ["sink"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A clearance of at least ________ inches shall be provided at the front of a shower opening.",
			"answer": ["24"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Showers and bathrubs with installed shower heads shall be finished with a nonabsorbent surface extending to a height of not less than _______ feet above the floor.",
			"answer": ["6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Glazing in all fixed and operable panels of swinging, sliding and bifold doors shall be considered a ________ _________.",
			"answer": ["hazardous", "location"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A pane of glass in a window requires safety glazing if the pane is greater than _______ square feet with a bottom edge less than ________ inches above the floor and a top edge greater than ________ inches above the floor.",
			"answer": ["9", "18", "36"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Glazing at the side of a stairway where the bottom exposed edge of glazing is less than ________ inches above the plane of the adjacent walking surface must be safety glazing.",
			"answer": ["36"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Glazing less than _______ inches above the landing at the bottom of the stairway and within ______ inches of the bottom tread nosing must be safety glazing.",
			"answer": ["36", "60"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Garage floor surfaces shall be of approved _______ material.",
			"answer": ["noncombustible"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Carports shall be open on at least _______ sides.",
			"answer": ["2"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Basements, habitable attics and every sleeping room shall have at least one operable _______ _______ and ________ __________.",
			"answer": ["emergency", "escape", "rescue", "opening"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where emergency escape and rescue openings are provided are provided, they shall have a sill height of not more than ______ inches above the floor.",
			"answer": ["44"]
		},
		{
			"question": "All emergency escape and rescue openings shall have a minimum net clear opening of ______ square feet. Minimum net clear opening height shall be ______ inches. Minimum net clear opening width shall be ______ inches.",
			"answer": ["5.7", "24", "20]
		},
		{
			"question": "The horizontal area of a window well serving an emergency escape and rescue opening shall be not less than ______ square feet.",
			"answer": ["9"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Window wells serving emergency escape and rescue openings shall be designed for proper ________.",
			"answer": ["drainage"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The required egress door for each dwelling unit shall be side-hinged, and shall provide a minimum clear width of ________ inches.",
			"answer": ["32"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A landing at an exterior door shall have a minimum dimension of _______ inches measured in the direction of travel.",
			"answer": ["36"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The landing on exterior side of the required egress door is permitted to be a maximum of ______ inches below the top of the threshold provided that the door does not swing over the landing.",
			"answer": ["7.75"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The width of a hallway shall be not less than ______ feet.",
			"answer": ["3"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where a handrail is installed on one side, the clear width of stairways at handrail height shall be a minimum of ______ inches.",
			"answer": ["31.5"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A flight of stairs shall not have a vertical rise larger than _______ inches between floor levels or landings.",
			"answer": ["151"]
		},
		{
			"question": "There shall be a floor or _________ at the top and bottom of each stairway.",
			"answer": ["landing"]
		},
		{
			"question": "For stairs with a straight run, the landing shall have a minimum depth of ______ inches measured in the direction of travel.",
			"answer": ["36"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Ramps shall have a maximum slope of _______ unit vertical in _______ units horizontal (8.3-percent slope). where serving the required egress door.",
			"answer": ["1", "12"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Stairways shall be not less than _______ inches in clear width at all points above the permitted handrail height and below the required headroom height.",
			"answer": ["36"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Is plastic composite material permitted for use as exterior stair treads?",
			"answer": ["Yes"]
		},
		{
			"question": "On stairways, the maximum riser height shall be _______ inches.",
			"answer": ["7.75"]
		},
		{
			"question": "On stairways, the minimum tread depth shall be _______ inches.",
			"answer": ["10"]
		},
		{
			"question": "On stairways, the greatest riser height within any flight of stairs shall not exceed the smallest by more than _______ inch.",
			"answer": ["3/8"]
		},
		{
			"question": "On stairways, the greatest tread depth within any flgiht of stairs shall not exceed the smallest by more than _____ inches.",
			"answer": ["3/8"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A nosing projection not less than _______ inch and not more than _______ inches shall be provided on stairways.",
			"answer": ["3/4", "1.25"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The headroom in all parts of the stairway shall be not less than _______ feet ________ inches.",
			"answer": ["6", "8"]
		},
		{
			"question": "On spiral stairways, the minimum width shall be _______ inches. The rise shall be not more than __________ inches between treads. A minimum headroom of ______ feet ______ inches shall be provided.",
			"answer": ["26", "9.5", "6", "6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Handrail height shall be a minimum of ______ inches and a maximum of _______ inches.",
			"answer": ["34", "38"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Handrails adjacent to a wall shall have a space of not less than _______ inches between the wall and the handrails.",
			"answer": ["1.5"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Type I handrails shall have a circular cross section shall have an outside diameter of at least _______ inches and not greater than ______ inches.",
			"answer": ["1.25", "2"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Open-sided walking surfaces located more than ______ inches above the floor or grade below shall have guards not less than _______ inches in height.",
			"answer": ["30", "36"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Required guards shall not have openings from the walking surface to the required guard height that allow passage of a sphere _______ inches in diameter.",
			"answer": ["4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "An automatic residential fire sprinkler system is not required where ______ or _______ are made to existing townhouses that do not have an automatic residential fire sprinkler system.",
			"answer": ["additions", "alterations"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Smoke alarms shall be installed in the following locations:",
			"answer": ["bedrooms", "outside bedrooms", "on each additional story of the dwelling"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Photoelectric smoke alarms shall not be installed less than _______ feet horizontally from a permanently installed cooking appliance.",
			"answer": ["6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Required smoke alarms shall receive their primary power from the building wiring, and when primary power is interrupted, shall receive power from a _________.",
			"answer": ["battery"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Physical interconnection of smoke alarms is not required when ________ ________ alarms are installed.",
			"answer": ["listed wireless"]
		},
		{
			"question": "For new construction, an approved carbon monoxide alarm shall be installed in what locations?",
			"answer": ["oustide of each bedroom"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Foam plastic shall have a flame spread index of not more than _______ and shall have a smoke-developed index of not more than ________.",
			"answer": ["75", "450"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Foam plastic shall be separated from the interior of a building by an approved ______ _________ of not less than _______ inch gypsum wallboard.",
			"answer": ["thermal barrier", "1/2"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A thermal barrier is not required for foam plastic insulation in an attic that is entered only for purposes of ________ or _________.",
			"answer": ["repairs", "maintenance"]
		},
		{
			"question": "In areas where the probability of termite infestation is \"very heavy\", the clearance between foam plastics installed above grade and exposed earth shall be at least ______ inches.",
			"answer": ["6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Dwelling units in two-family dwellings shall be separated from each other by wall and floor assemblies having not less than _______ -hour fire-resistance rating.",
			"answer": ["1"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Protection of wood and wood-based products from ________ shall be provided in specified locations by the use of naturally durable wood or wood that is preservative-treated.",
			"answer": ["decay"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Address numbers shall be a minimum of _______ inches high with a minimum stroke width of _______ inch.",
			"answer": ["4", "0.5]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where there are ________ or more dwelling units in a single structure, the accessibility provisions of IBC Chapter 11 for Group R-3 shall apply.",
			"answer": ["4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "In flood hazard areas, enclosed areas below the design flood elevation shall be used solely for:",
			"answer": ["parking of vehicles", "building access", "storage"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where photovoltaic panels are installed on a roof, a pathway at least _______ inches in width shall be provided to each emergency escape and rescue opening.",
			"answer": ["36"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The design and consstruction of pools and spas shall comply with the ________.",
			"answer": ["International Swimming Pool and Spa Code"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The grade away from foundation walls shall fall minimum of ________ inches within the first ________ feet.",
			"answer": ["6","10"]
		},
		{
			"question": "In Seismic Design Categories D0, D1, and D2, foundations with stem walls shall be provided with a minimum of one No. ________ horizontal bar within 12 inches of the top of the wall and one No. _______ horizontal bar located 3 to 5 inches from the bottom of the footing.",
			"answer": ["4","4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "All exterior footings shall be placed at least _______ inches below the undisturbed ground surface.",
			"answer": ["12"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The top surface of footing shall be level. The bottom surface of footings shall not have a slope exceeding _____ unit vertical in ________ units horizontal.",
			"answer": ["1","10"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Wood sill plates shall be anchored to the foundation with anchor bolts spaced a maximum of _______ feet on center.",
			"answer": ["6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Foundation anchor bolts shall be at least ______ inch in diameter and shall extend a minimum of ________ inches into concrete or grouted cells of concrete masonry units.",
			"answer": [".5", "7"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Isolated hollow masonry piers shall have a minimum nominal thickness of _______ inches.",
			"answer": ["8"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Hollow masonry piers shall be capped with ______ inches of solid masonry or concrete or a masonry cap block.",
			"answer": ["4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The studs used in wood foundation walls shall be ______-inch by ______-inch members.",
			"answer": ["2","6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Wood sill plates shall be a minimum of _______-inch by _______-inch nominal lumber.",
			"answer": ["2","4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Unless otherwise recommended by the drain manufacturer, perforated foundation drains shall be surrounded with an approved ______ ________.",
			"answer": ["Filter Membrane"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Steel pipe columns shall be not less than ______ inches in diameter.",
			"answer": ["3"]
		},
		{
			"question": "In under-floor spaces, the minimum net area of ventilation openings shall be not less than ________ square foot for each ________ square feet of under-floor space area.",
			"answer": ["1","150"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Ventilation openings in under-floor spaces are not required where the ground is covered with a continuous ________ vapor retarder and the joints overlap at least _______ inches.",
			"answer": ["Class I","6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The minimum required floor access opening to all under-floor spaces shall be ______ inches by _______ inches.",
			"answer": ["18", "24"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Open web truss or I-joint floor assemblies are required to have a ______-inch gypsum wallboard membrane, _______-inch wood structural panel membrane, or equivalent on the underside of the floor framing member.",
			"answer": [".5", "5/8"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The ends of each floor joist, beam or girder shall have not less than ______ inches of bearing on wood or metal and not less than ______ inches of bearing on masonry or concrete.",
			"answer": ["1.5", "3"]
		},
		{
			"question": "NOtches in solid lumber joists, rafters and beams shall be exceed _______ of the depth, shall not be longer than ________ of the depth and shall not be located in the middle ________ of the span.",
			"answer": ["1/6", "1/3", "1/3"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The tension side of floor joist members ______ inches or greater in nominal thickness shall not be notched except at the ends of the members.",
			"answer": ["4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where the header joist span does not exceed _______ feet, the header joist may be a single member the same size as the floor joist.",
			"answer": ["4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "In combustible contruction where there is usable space both above and below a floor-ceiling assembly, draftstops shall be installed so that the area of the concealed space does not exceed ______ square feet.",
			"answer": ["1000"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The provisions of Section R505 Coldformed Steel Floor Framing shall control the construction of cold-formed steel floor framing for buildings not greater than _____ feet in length perpendicular to the joist span.",
			"answer": ["60"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Flanges and lips of load-bearing cold-formed steel floor framing members shall not be cut or ______.",
			"answer": ["notched"]
		},
		{
			"question": "In cold-formed steel framing, floor cantilevers for the top floor of a two- or three-story building or the first floor of a one-story building shall not exceed _______ inches.",
			"answer": ["24"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Concrete slab-on-ground floors shall be a minimum of _______ inches thick.",
			"answer": ["3.5"]
		},
		{
			"question": "For wood stud walls capped with a double top plate, end joints in top plates shall be offset at least _______ inches.",
			"answer": ["24"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where joists, trusses or rafters are spaced more than 16 inches on center and the bearing studs below are spaced 24 inches on center, such members shall bear within _______ inches of the studs beneath.",
			"answer": ["5"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Any wood stud in an exterior wall or bearing partition may be cut or notched to a depth not exceeding ______ percent of its width.",
			"answer": ["25"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Wood studs in nonbearing partitions may be notched to a depth not exceeding ______ percent a single stud width.",
			"answer": ["40"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Exterior wood frame walls parallel to a braced wall line shall be offset not more than ______ feet from the designated braced wall line location.",
			"answer": ["4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Braced wall lines greater than 16 feet shall have a minimum of ______ braced wall panels.",
			"answer": ["2"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Wall bracing Method PFG (Portal frame at garage door opening) is limited to walls supporting a roof or _______ and a ________.",
			"answer": ["one-story", "roof"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Unfaced fiberglass batt insulation is _______ to be used for fireblocking.",
			"answer": ["permitted"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Braced wall panels shall be contructed with intermittent bracing methods and continuous sheathing methods. Mixing bracing methods shall be _________.",
			"answer": ["permitted"]
		},
		{
			"question": "In order to use the simplified wall bracing methods, the building must be located where the ultimate design wind speed is less than or equal to _______ mph.",
			"answer": ["130"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Load-bearing cold-formed steel studs shall be located in-line with joists, trusses and rafters with a maximum tolerance of ______ inch between the centerline of the horizontal and vertical framing members.",
			"answer": [".75"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Web holes in steel wall studs shall not exceed _______ inches in width or _______ inches in length.",
			"answer": ["1.5","4.5"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Steel studs and other structural members shall not be _________.",
			"answer": ["spliced"]
		},
		{
			"question": "In cold-formed steel framing, king, jack and cripple studs shall be the same dimension and thickness as the adjacent ______ studs.",
			"answer": ["wall"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The minimum thickness of masonry bearing walls more than one story high shall be _______ inches.",
			"answer": ["8"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Solid masonry walls of one-story dwellings and garages shall be not less than ________ inches in thickness where not greater than 9 feet in height.",
			"answer": ["6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Grout shall not be pumped though _______ pipes.",
			"answer": ["aluminum"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The provisions for structural insulated panel walls are limited to buildings not greater than ______ stories in height with each wall not greater than ____ feet high.",
			"answer": ["2","10"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Wood wall framing supporting 3/8 inch gypsum board shall not be spaced more than _______ inches on center.",
			"answer": ["16"]
		},
		{
			"question": "For a water-resistive barrier on an exterior wall, felt shall be applied horizontally with the upper layer lapped over the lower layer not less than _______ inches.",
			"answer": ["2"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Anchored stone an masonry veneer installed over a backing of wood or cold-formed steel shall be limited to the first story above grade and shall not exceed _______ inches in thickness.",
			"answer": ["5"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Masonry veneer above openings shall be supported on lintels of ________ materials.",
			"answer": ["noncombustible"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where using W1.7 wire ties with hooks, stone or masonry veneer shall be separated from the sheathing by an airspace of a minimum of _______ inch but not more than _______ inches.",
			"answer": ["1","4.5"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Weepholes in masonry veneer shall be not less than _______ inch in diameter with a maximum spacing of _______ inches on center.",
			"answer": ["3/16", "33"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Collar ties shall be a minimum of 1 inch by 4 inches, spaced not more than _______ feet on center.",
			"answer": ["4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Attic ventilation openings shall have a least dimension of _______ inch minimum and ________ inch maximum.",
			"answer": ["1/16", "1/4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Attic access rough-framed openings shall be not less than _______ inches by _______ inches.",
			"answer": ["22", "30"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Except for Type IC luminaires, thermal insulation shall not be installed above a recessed luminaire or within _______ inches of the recessed luminaire's enclosure.",
			"answer": ["3"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A cricket or saddle shall be installed on the ridge side of any chimney more than _______ inches wide as measured perpendicular to the slope.",
			"answer": ["30"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where the roof sheathing is less than _______ inch thick, the fasteners for asphalt shingles shall penetrate through the sheathing.",
			"answer": ["3/4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Asphalt shingles shall be secured to the roof with less than _________ fasteners per strip shingle or ___________ fasteners per individual shingle.",
			"answer": ["4","2"]
		},
		{
			"question": "At the intersection of asphalt shingles with a vertical sidewall, flashing shall be a minimum of _______ inches in height and ________ inches in width.",
			"answer": ["4", "4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Roof drip edges shall be mechanically fastened to the roof deck at a maximum of _________ inches on center.",
			"answer": ["12"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Wood shakes shall only be used on slopes of _______ units vertical in ________ units horizontal or greater.",
			"answer": ["3", "12"]
		},
		{
			"question": "For wood shakes roofs, valley flashing shall be not less than No. _________ gage corrosion-resistant sheet metal.",
			"answer": ["26"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Masonry chimney walls or chimney flue linings shall not chnage in size or shape within _______ inches above or below where the chimney passes through floor, ceiling or roof components.",
			"answer": ["6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Chimneys shall extend at least _______ feet higher than any portion of a building widthin ________ feet.",
			"answer": ["2", "10"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Masonry chimney walls shall be constructed of solid masonry units or hollow masonry units grouted solid with less than a ________ inch nomial thickness.",
			"answer": ["4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Any portion of a masonry chimney located in the interior of a building or widthin an exterior wall shall have a minimum airspace clearance to combustibles of _______ inches.",
			"answer": ["2"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Exterior masonry chimneys that pass through a soffit or cornice shall have a minimum airspace clearance of __________ inch.",
			"answer": ["1"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Footings for masonry chimneys shall be constructed of concrete or solid masonry at least _______ inches thick.",
			"answer": ["12"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The minimum thickness of masonry fireplace hearths shall be _______ inches.",
			"answer": ["4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where a masonry fireplace opening is less than 6 quare feet, hearth extensions shall extend at least _______ inches in front of and at least ______ inches beyond each side of the fireplace opening.",
			"answer": ["16", "8"]
		},
		{
			"question": "For masonry fireplace openings 6 square feet or larger, hearth extensions shall extend at least _______ inches in front of and at least _______ inches beyond each side of the fireplace opening.",
			"answer": ["20", "12"]
		},
		{
			"question": "All wood beams, joists, studs and other combustible material shall have a clearance of not less than ________ inches from the front faces and sides of masonry fireplaces.",
			"answer": ["2"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Combustible material within ________ inches of the fireplace opening shall not project more than 1/8 inch for each 1-inch distance from such an opening.",
			"answer": ["12"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Chapter 11 regulates the _______ efficiency for the desing and contruction of building regulated by this code.",
			"answer": ["energy"]
		},
		{
			"question": "For mechanical systems, a level working space at least _______ inches deep and _______ inches wide shall be provided in front of the control side to service an appliance.",
			"answer": ["30", "30"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where mechanical equipment is located in attics, it shall not be farther than _______ feet from the attic access.",
			"answer": ["20"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Attics containing mechanical appliances shall be provided with an opening and a clear and unobstructed passageway to allow removal of the ________ appliance.",
			"answer": ["largest"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Mechanical appliances installed in attics shall have a luminaire controlled by a switch located at the required ______ ______ and a receptacle outlet provided at or near the appliance location.",
			"answer": ["passageway","opening"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Mechanical appliances suspended from the floor shall have a clearance of not less than ________ inches from the ground.",
			"answer": ["6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Mechanical appliances having an ignition source shall be elevated such that the source of ignition is not less than ______ inches above the floor in garages.",
			"answer": ["18"]
		},
		{
			"question": "_________ shall not be installed at the termination of a clothes dryer exhaust duct.",
			"answer": ["Screens"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Clothes dryer exhaust ducts shall not be ______ inches nominal in diameter.",
			"answer": ["4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A 4-inch radius mitered 45-degree elbow dryer exhuast duct fitting shall reduce the maximum 35-foot length of dryer duct by _______ feet ________ inches.",
			"answer": ["2", "6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where space for a ________ ________ is provided, an exhaust duct system shall be installed.",
			"answer": ["clothes","dryer"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Crimp joints for round and oval metal ducts shall be lapped not less than ______ inch(es).",
			"answer": ["1"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Under-floor plenums shall be _______ in new structures.",
			"answer": ["prohibited"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Return air for a forced-air heating or cooling system shall not be taken from ________.",
			"answer": ["bathrooms", "toilets", "kitchens", "closets", "garages", "mechanical", "boiler", "furnace", "attics"]
		},
		{
			"question": "For mechanical system installations in flood hazard areas, _______ ________ openings shall be located at or above the required elevation.",
			"answer": ["combustion","air"]
		},
		{
			"question": "For gas appliance installations using the two-permanent-openings method for outdoor combustion air, one opening shall be within ______ inches of the top and one within _______ inches of the bottom of the space.",
			"answer": ["12", "12"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Manually operated vent _______ shall not be installed except in connectors or chimneys serving solid fuel-burning appliances.",
			"answer": ["dampers"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Freestanding or built-in ranges shall have a vertical clearance above the cooking top of not less than ________ inches to unprotected combustible material.",
			"answer": ["30"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Sauna heaters shall be equipped with a thermostat that will limit room temperature to not greater than _______ degrees Fahrenheit.",
			"answer": ["194"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Boiler pressure relief valve discharge shall be piped to drains by gravity to within _______ inches of the floor or to an open receptor.",
			"answer": ["18"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Polyethylene tubing for hydronic piping system shall be installed with _______ - _______ joints.",
			"answer": ["heat", "fusion"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The maximum amount of fuel oil stored above ground or inside a building shall be __________ gallons.",
			"answer": ["660"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Vent piping on oil tanks shall be not smaller than _______ - inch pipe.",
			"answer": ["1.25"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Oil tank vent piping shall terminate outside of buildings at a point not less than _______ feet, measured vertically or horizontally, from any building opening.",
			"answer": ["2"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Components of a solar thermal energy system that might be subject to a vacuum during operation or shutdown shall be protected by _______ ________ _________ unless designed to withstand such a vacuum.",
			"answer": ["vacuum", "relief", "valves"]
		},
		{
			"question": "BTU is the abbreviation for ________ _________ _________, which is the quantity of heat required to raise the temperature of 1 pout of water 1 degree Fahrenheit.",
			"answer": ["British", "Thermal", "Unit"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Fuel gas piping installed across roof surfaces shall be elevated not less than _______ inches above the roof surface.",
			"answer": ["3.5"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where gas piping is concealed and run within _________ inches from the framing member face to which the membranes will be attached, it shall be protected by shield plates.",
			"answer": ["1.5"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Shield plates, where required to cover the area of concealed gas piping, shall be a minimum No. __________ gage.",
			"answer": ["16"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Underground fuel gas piping systems shall be installed a minimum depth of ______ inches below grade.",
			"answer": ["12"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Gas appliance shutoff valves shall be located in the same room as the appliance and not farther than _________ feet from the appliance.",
			"answer": ["6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Fuel gas appliance connectors shall not exceed an overall length of _______ feet.",
			"answer": ["6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Gas vents over 12 inches in size shall terminate not less than ________ feet above the highest point where they pass through the roof.",
			"answer": ["2"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A Type B or Type L gass vent shall terminate at least ________ feet vertical height above the highest connected appliance draft hood or flue collar.",
			"answer": ["5"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A Type B-W gas vent shall terminate at least _______ feet in vertical height above the bottom of a wall furnace.",
			"answer": ["12"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Vent connectors for draft-hood-equipped appliances shall not be _______ than the draft hood outlet diameter.",
			"answer": ["smaller"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The lowest portion of a gas floor furnace shall have not less than a ________-inch clearance from grade level.",
			"answer": ["6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "What size diameter is required for fuel-gas-fired domestic clothes dryer exhaust ducts?",
			"answer": ["4","inches"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Domestic clothes dryer transition ducts shall be metal and limited to a single length not to exceed _______ feet.",
			"answer": ["8"]
		},
		{
			"question": "When doing a water test on DWV systems during rough-in plumbing, each section shall be filled with water to a point not less than _________ feet above the highest fitting in that section.",
			"answer": ["5"]
		},
		{
			"question": "When doing an air test on DWV systems during rough-in plumbing, the portion under test shall be maintained at ________ psi for _________ minutes.",
			"answer": ["5", "15"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Water service pipe shall be installed not less than _______ inches deep and not less than _________ inches below the frost line.",
			"answer": ["12", "6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Trenching installed parallel to footings shall not extend below the ________ - degree bearing plane of the bottom edge of a wall or footing.",
			"answer": ["45"]
		},
		{
			"question": "In plumbing systems, supports for 1-inch copper or copper alloy tubing run horizontal shall not be spaced more than ________ feet apart.",
			"answer": ["6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Fixture tail pieces shall be not less than _______ inches in diameter for sinks, dishwashers, laundry tubs, bathtubs and similar fixtures.",
			"answer": ["1.5"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The center line of water closets or bidets shall not be set less than _______ inches from adjacent side walls or partitions.",
			"answer": ["15"]
		},
		{
			"question": "There shall be at least ________ inches of clearance in front of the water closet, bidet, or lavatory to any wall, fixture or door.",
			"answer": ["21"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Standpipes shall extend a minimum of ________ inches and a maximum of _______ inches above the trap weir.",
			"answer": ["18", "42"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Shower compartments shall have at least ________ square inches of interior cross-sectional area.",
			"answer": ["900"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Lavatories shall have waste outlets not less than ________ inches in diameter.",
			"answer": ["1.25"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Bathtubs shall be equipped with waste outlets and overflow outlets connected to piping at least ________ inches in diameter.",
			"answer": ["1.5"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Sinks shall be provided with waste outlets not less than _______ inches in diameter.",
			"answer": ["1.5"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Each compartment of a laundry tub shall be provided with a waste outlet not less than _______ inches in diameter.",
			"answer": ["1.5"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Floor drains shall have waste outlets not less than _______ inches in diameter and a removable strainer.",
			"answer": ["2"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Bottom fed tank-type water heaters and bottom fed tanks connected to water heaters shall have a ______ ______ valve installed.",
			"answer": ["vacuum", "relief"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The maximum static pressure of a water service shall be ________ psi.",
			"answer": ["80"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The minimum size water service pipe shall be ________ inch.",
			"answer": ["3/4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A _______ - __________ fire sprinkler system shall be seperate and independent from the water distribution system.",
			"answer": ["stand", "alone"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The fire sprinkler water supply shall provide the required design flow rate for ________ minutes for one-story dwelling units less than ________ square feet in area.",
			"answer": ["7","2000"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where chlorine is used for disinfection in nonpotable water systems, the water shall contain not more than ________ ppm of chloramines or free chlorine.",
			"answer": ["4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The drainage fixture unit (d.f.u.) value of a dishwasher is __________.",
			"answer": ["2"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Any combination of fixtures within two bathroom groups located on the same floor level are __________ to be vented by a horizontal wet vent.",
			"answer": ["permitted"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Storm drainage sump pumps shall be of a capacity and head appropriate to _________ use requirements.",
			"answer": ["anticipated"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Electrical services within the scope of the IRC are limited to _________ volt, 0- to ________ -ampere, single-phase systems.",
			"answer": ["120/240","400"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The markings for identification of disconnecting means shall have the durability to withstand the _________ involved.",
			"answer": ["environment"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Electrical panelboards and overcurrent devices shall not be located in __________.",
			"answer": ["clothes","closets","bathrooms","stairway","closets"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Connected to establish electrical continuity and conductivity.",
			"answer": ["bonded"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Overhead service-drop conductors shall have a vertical clearance of not less than _______ feet above the roof surface.",
			"answer": ["8"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Over residential property and driveways, service-drop conductors shall have _________ feet minimum clearance above final grade.",
			"answer": ["12"]
		},
		{
			"question": "In no case shall the point of attachment for service-drop conductors be less than _______ feet above finished grade.",
			"answer": ["10"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Above-ground service-entrance cables subject to physical damage shall be protected by Schedule ___________ PVC conduit",
			"answer": ["80"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Interior metal water piping located more than ________ feet from the point of entrance to the building shall not be used to connect electrodes as part of the grounding electrode system.",
			"answer": ["5"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Rod an pipe electrodes shall be not less than _________ feet in length.",
			"answer": ["8"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Bonding shall be provided where necessary to ensure electrical __________.",
			"answer": ["continuity"]
		},
		{
			"question": "All mechanical elements used to terminate a grounding electrode conductor or bonding jumper to the grounding electrodes shall be __________.",
			"answer": ["accessible"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where a branch circuit or feeder supplies a continuous load, it shall have an ampacity of at least the noncontinuous load plus ________ percent of continuous load.",
			"answer": ["125"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The rating of any one cord-and-plug-connected utilization equipment shall not exceed ________ percent of the branch-circuit ampere rating.",
			"answer": ["80"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Branch circuit ratings for space-heating and water-heating appliances shall be considered ________ loads.",
			"answer": ["continuous"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A minimum of ____________ 20-ampere-rated branch circuits shall be provided to serve all wall and floor receptacle outlets located in the kitchen, pantry, breakfast area, dining area or similar area of a dwelling.",
			"answer": ["2"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A minimum of one ________-ampere-rated branch circuit shall be provided for receptacles located in the laundry area and shall serve only receptacle outlets in the laundry area.",
			"answer": ["20"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A minimum of ___________ 20-ampere rated branch circuit(s) shall be provided to supply the bathroom receptacle outlet(s). Such circuits shall have no other outlets.",
			"answer": ["1"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Conductors in NM cable assemblies shall be rated at _________ degrees Celsius.",
			"answer": ["90"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Insulated conductors and cables exposed to direct rays of the sun shall be listed and labeled as ________ _________.",
			"answer": ["sunlight", "resistant"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Where raceways are installed in wet locations above grade, the interior of such raceways shall be considered to be a ________ location.",
			"answer": ["wet"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Underground service laterals that are not encased in concrete and that are buried 18 inches or more below grade shall have their location identified by a _______ _________.",
			"answer": ["warning", "ribbon"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Receptacles shall be installed so that no point along the floor line in any wall space is more than _______ feet, measured horizontally, from an outlet in that space.",
			"answer": ["6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Kitchen wall countertop and work surface receptacles shall be installed so that no point along the wall line is more than ________ inches from a receptacle.",
			"answer": ["24"]
		},
		{
			"question": "At least one receptacle outlet in bathrooms is required to be within _______ inches of the outside edge of each lavatory basin.",
			"answer": ["36"]
		},
		{
			"question": "There shall be a wall switch at each floor to control stairway lighting where the stairway has _________ or more risers.",
			"answer": ["6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Nonmetallic boxes shall be used only with cabled wiring methods with entirely nonmetallic sheaths, flexible cords and nonmetallic raceways.",
			"answer": ["True"]
		},
		{
			"question": "In calculating box fill, each No. 12 AWG conductor shall require _________ cubic inches of free space within the box.",
			"answer": ["2.25"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Unused openings in cabinets and panelboards shall be effectively _________ to afford protection equivalent to that of the wall of the cabinet.",
			"answer": ["closed"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The _________ shall not be considered as an effective ground-fault current path.",
			"answer": ["earth"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Switches for devices and luminaires shall not be more than ________ feet ______ inches above the floor or working platform when the switch is in its highest position.",
			"answer": ["6","7"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Receptacles installed on 15- and 20- ampere-rated branch circuits shall be of the ______ type.",
			"answer": ["grounding"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Recessed incadescent fixtures shall have ________ protection.",
			"answer": ["thermal"]
		},
		{
			"question": "In clothes closets, surface-mounted incandescent luminaires shall have ________ inches of minimum clearance from the nearest point of a storage space.",
			"answer": ["12"]
		},
		{
			"question": "A luminaire that weighs more than _______ pounds or exceeds 16 inches in any dimension shall not be supported by the screw shell of a lampholder.",
			"answer": ["6"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Flexible cords for kitchen range hoods shall be _______ inches minimum and ________ inches maximum length.",
			"answer": ["18", "48"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Ceiling-suspended paddle fans shall be supported ___________ of an outlet box.",
			"answer": ["independently"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Cords that supply swimming pool equipment shall have a copper equipment grounding conductor not smaller than No. _________ AWG.",
			"answer": ["12"]
		}
	]
}
